<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>daily on Marty S Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://martysohio.com/categories/daily/</link>
    <description>Recent content in daily on Marty S Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martysohio.com/categories/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal Garden Update</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/06/near-daily-journal-garden-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/06/near-daily-journal-garden-update/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts and garden update In a sort of test run for market gardening, our garden is quite larger this year. Its had a rough start. Early April had some warm days so I took a gamble and planted two rows of beans on April 3rd. One managed to come up and survived, and looks pretty pitiful. Bush beans usually have ~60 day maturity. And here we are 60+ days in and they are only flowering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal May Update 2020-05-31</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-may-update-2020-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-may-update-2020-05-31/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts Wow what a month. Got my birthday out of the way, and tons of gardening. Switched over to 30 inch beds for the rest of the beans, and they will probably come out much better than the initial rows. The single rows all look terrible. But the corn is doing great.
Things are starting to open up in Ohio, again. Like the activities our kids were enrolled in prior to the shutdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-05-02</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-2020-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-2020-05-02/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts The weater turned out to be really good. It was predicted to be windy + gusty but that didn&amp;rsquo;t come up until the late evening. Then thunderstorm at night. The in-laws were able to come over and hang out with the boys. Plus got a lot of yard work done. The gardens are slowly getting there. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for a big push in planting by mid-May. Out of two rows of bush beans planted in early April, one is coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-21</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-21/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts Let the last few day slip by, but finally some relief from the quarantine. The in-laws isolated themselves for most of the past month. So did we. Finally they decided it was worth the risk to have us over. Other members of the family are in more risky occupations. Luckily we only work from home. So interactions outside the house have been minimal. Plus the luck of being in Portage county where COVID-19 cases are relatively low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-26</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-26/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts The weather is warming. On the 25th it was bright and sunny, well above 60F - 65 ? Perfect to be outside all day. And we were. Started off with our neighbors giving us a ton of horse poop (literally) that had been composting on the side of one of their pastures. It will help immensely with improving the soil on the expanded garden. Turning it over has been tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-17</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-17/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts In lieu of a journal, thought I start trying to throw short things out here. Today its freezing and lightly snowing. The last gasp of winter. After this the forecast looks like 50 degrees and higher. Of course, this weather was summoned by my attempt to plant beans early. They haven&amp;rsquo;t sprouted so they may yet live. The initial carrots got washed out. So far gardening is a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>