<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marty S Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://martysohio.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marty S Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 13:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martysohio.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterloo Levy fails again</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/waterloo-levy-fails-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/waterloo-levy-fails-again/</guid>
      <description>In Ohio, school districts are about 50% funded via the local school district population. Additional funding comes from the state based on the number of students. It is a terrible system that was ruled unconstitutional in the 90s and really not much has changed despite the ruling. For the curious, there are innumerable better sources on why and how that is out there on the Internet.
My local district Waterloo is no exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Py Pong starter</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/10/py-pong-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/10/py-pong-starter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with PyGame and its certainly a trip. Game logic is much easier than the mechanics of drawing something in the proper order and the proper way. It took way longer than I expected to get a basic version of Pong functional. Needs some final tweaks to beat the 80&amp;frasl;20 rule and have something that is truly complete. I keep redoing it as I find something else out about PyGame and game logic in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable App Grouping in Linux Mint 19 Taskbar</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/09/disable-app-grouping-in-linux-mint-19-taskbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/09/disable-app-grouping-in-linux-mint-19-taskbar/</guid>
      <description>Simple fluff here. Took me a while to hunt down this feature. I switched to the latest Mint, and the applications all group by type like this -
If you have an Incognito tab or multiple folders, its a bit annoying for me to hover and flip through and I like to click rather than Alt+Tab or some other window switching method.
To change it:
 Right click empty space on the taskbar, click + Add Applets to Panel  Select Grouped Window List from the next menu and click the gear icon next to it In the next window untoggle the Group windows by application option   And thats it, now all your applications will be spread out even with multiples of the same app open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker Rank Special Multiple</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/07/hacker-rank-special-multiple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/07/hacker-rank-special-multiple/</guid>
      <description>Not a hard one: You are given an integer N. Can you find the least positive integer X made up of only 9&#39;s and 0&#39;s, such that, X is a multiple of N?
Any number consisting of just 9s and 0s is divisible by 9. I see a few ways to use that, also 9s and 0s are two unique characters, so another way would be to process numbers are strings matching those characters rather than evaluating every multiple of N until you hit one thats divisible by 9, as something can be divisible by 9 but not be only 9s and 0s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Geese - Nature&#39;s Satanic Cult</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/06/canadian-geese---natures-satanic-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/06/canadian-geese---natures-satanic-cult/</guid>
      <description>Geese are a scourge Since my wife and I are getting old, we&amp;rsquo;ve taken up gardening and with age comes us getting better at it. So of course this year I wanted to try the Three Sisters method of planting. I would plant corn, beans and squash together to maximize the output for a given area, and it would take a bit less work.
In the spirit of overdoing it, our neighbor was kind enough to use his big Kobota tractor with a tiller attachment to grind up a big area in our backyard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 3 - The End</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/04/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-3---the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/04/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-3---the-end/</guid>
      <description>Out the door Leading up to the first weekend away, we called and sent an email to the case worker. We wanted confirmation the children would be able to go to their Aunt&amp;rsquo;s for the weekend. Instead of confirmation (which we had gotten verbally), my wife got a bit of a dressing down over the phone (or at one of their schedule visits, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember which). Paraphrasing - the worker more or less said no one involved had the right to make those decisions except her/Cuyahoga county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-2/</guid>
      <description>On the way Despite the stress for everyone involved, we were aware our placements would be leaving us by summer, at least as of January. In February, we were summoned for what was called a staffing meeting. This is where various parties related to the case gather together and discuss things that could be in an email.
The meeting did not really concern us, though my wife and I were both present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-1/</guid>
      <description>Foster care sure was something On October 26th, we got a call about our first foster placement. In the month prior, we had taken a few weekend cases for respite care. Respite care is babysitting for other foster parents. Then they can take a break or take care of a few things. Leading into the proper placement, respite care went ok. It was a bit hard since the kids were so young and couldn&amp;rsquo;t bond with us over a weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random thoughts</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2018/12/random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2018/12/random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This timeline is weird If you&amp;rsquo;d told me 15 years ago, I would have two kids and be fostering two more, I&amp;rsquo;d have called you nuts. I&amp;rsquo;ve turned into everyone&amp;rsquo;s dad. The stampede of footsteps every morning is my alarm clock. And my day is a constant stream of the question &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo;.
Expectation never meets reality, and I&amp;rsquo;m not unhappy at all. People think you can make precarious plans and follow them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>