<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marty S Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://martysohio.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marty S Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martysohio.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal Garden Update</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/06/near-daily-journal-garden-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/06/near-daily-journal-garden-update/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts and garden update In a sort of test run for market gardening, our garden is quite larger this year. Its had a rough start. Early April had some warm days so I took a gamble and planted two rows of beans on April 3rd. One managed to come up and survived, and looks pretty pitiful. Bush beans usually have ~60 day maturity. And here we are 60+ days in and they are only flowering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal May Update 2020-05-31</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-may-update-2020-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-may-update-2020-05-31/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts Wow what a month. Got my birthday out of the way, and tons of gardening. Switched over to 30 inch beds for the rest of the beans, and they will probably come out much better than the initial rows. The single rows all look terrible. But the corn is doing great.
Things are starting to open up in Ohio, again. Like the activities our kids were enrolled in prior to the shutdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-05-02</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-2020-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/05/near-daily-journal-2020-05-02/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts The weater turned out to be really good. It was predicted to be windy + gusty but that didn&amp;rsquo;t come up until the late evening. Then thunderstorm at night. The in-laws were able to come over and hang out with the boys. Plus got a lot of yard work done. The gardens are slowly getting there. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for a big push in planting by mid-May. Out of two rows of bush beans planted in early April, one is coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-21</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-21/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts Let the last few day slip by, but finally some relief from the quarantine. The in-laws isolated themselves for most of the past month. So did we. Finally they decided it was worth the risk to have us over. Other members of the family are in more risky occupations. Luckily we only work from home. So interactions outside the house have been minimal. Plus the luck of being in Portage county where COVID-19 cases are relatively low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-26</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-26/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts The weather is warming. On the 25th it was bright and sunny, well above 60F - 65 ? Perfect to be outside all day. And we were. Started off with our neighbors giving us a ton of horse poop (literally) that had been composting on the side of one of their pastures. It will help immensely with improving the soil on the expanded garden. Turning it over has been tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Daily Journal 2020-04-17</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/04/near-daily-journal-2020-04-17/</guid>
      <description>Daily thoughts In lieu of a journal, thought I start trying to throw short things out here. Today its freezing and lightly snowing. The last gasp of winter. After this the forecast looks like 50 degrees and higher. Of course, this weather was summoned by my attempt to plant beans early. They haven&amp;rsquo;t sprouted so they may yet live. The initial carrots got washed out. So far gardening is a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biden kind of sucks</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/biden-kind-of-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/biden-kind-of-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Shamelessly stole a lot of the links here from a post on SA, but thats ok, its for a good cause. Joe Biden is easily the worst Democratic party candidate for President I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in my lifetime. And the farthest I can remember back is Gore (but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t vote at the time). I expect he will be another portrait on the hall of shame, for innumerable reasons, come November. Gore was the worst loss, and should have been the canary in the coal mine for the party to start shifting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Giant Can Wake Again</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/the-giant-can-wake-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/the-giant-can-wake-again/</guid>
      <description>If COVID-19 continues its current course in the United States, we are certainly in for a ride. Several industries are in dire straits as a result. The healthcare sector is going to collapse entirely. If its pushed over by overwhelming cases of COVID-19. For-profit and non-profit hospitals are lacking equipment, staff, and space to deal with the possibility. This site has a run down. The reality is our hospital is designed for the average load at any given time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dying of superflu to own the libs</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/dying-of-superflu-to-own-the-libs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/03/dying-of-superflu-to-own-the-libs/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 is upon us, and all signs still point to the USA mirroring Italy. Due to our delay in testing and really doing anything at all, its still not really known how many cases are really out there and the rate they are spreading. However, as people are tested and what testing exists is rolled out, its clear we are experiencing exponential growth in cases throughout the country. According to the graph and data aggregated at worldometer, we&amp;rsquo;re getting 10x more cases every week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Pong Demo</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2020/01/godot-pong-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2020/01/godot-pong-demo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve played too many video games over the years, going back to the NES as the first system I recall owning, and cutting my teeth on the SNES for most of the 90s. Then moved onto nights of Goldeneye 64 and into the future of PC gaming. And for the longest time through most of college, I wanted to work on games in some way. However, turns out that is harder than it looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack Ryan is a funny show</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/12/jack-ryan-is-a-funny-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/12/jack-ryan-is-a-funny-show/</guid>
      <description>In the search for more shows to binge, I finally got around to watching Jack Ryan. MORE LIKE JIM RYAN, RIGHT ? But anyway, I am not sure which side the writers want the viewers to take. Like every other entry Jack Ryan media, the central character is an upstart wonk. He sits in a corner doing his work until duty calls. Then he is thrust back into action and becomes John Rambo as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Materialism is weird</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/12/materialism-is-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/12/materialism-is-weird/</guid>
      <description>When I was kid, every year around Christmas, through middle school, everyone was excited about potential gifts. For my peer group, the prized possession was any kind of gaming console and games. I.e. SNES/Gensis games, then Playstation 1/N64 up through the Dreamcast across the 90s.
Other kids had other dreams. In retrospect, those dreams were very materialistic. We all wanted things. No one was asking for experience or something intangible. Even the elementary school atmosphere encouraged materialism as a form of affection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Py Metis HTTP Monitor</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/py-metis-http-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/py-metis-http-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Making your own HTTP monitor without breaking the bank can be difficult if you need to scale your monitoring up to thousands of URLs. In most cases, you want to hit some URL every 5 minutes, sometimes every minute. If you have a long list of URLs, then you run into a few constraints:
 The scan of the URLs has to complete before the next run - monitoring every 5 minutes means your ping and processing has to take less than 5 minutes Jobs can&amp;rsquo;t overrun or you risk spamming your list with HTTP hits Processing the results into useful alerts can also constrain you, but there are multiple ways to approach alerting depending on your needs  I&amp;rsquo;ve seen implementations in Go that make it easier or some other language geared towards concurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterloo Levy Fails Again</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/waterloo-levy-fails-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/11/waterloo-levy-fails-again/</guid>
      <description>In Ohio, school districts are about 50% funded via the local school district population. Additional funding comes from the state based on the number of students. It is a terrible system that was ruled unconstitutional in the 90s and really not much has changed despite the ruling. For the curious, there are innumerable better sources on why and how that is out there on the Internet.
My local district Waterloo is no exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Py Pong Starter</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/10/py-pong-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/10/py-pong-starter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with PyGame and its certainly a trip. Game logic is much easier than the mechanics of drawing something in the proper order and the proper way. It took way longer than I expected to get a basic version of Pong functional. Needs some final tweaks to beat the 80/20 rule and have something that is truly complete. I keep redoing it as I find something else out about PyGame and game logic in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable App Grouping in Linux Mint 19 Taskbar</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/09/disable-app-grouping-in-linux-mint-19-taskbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/09/disable-app-grouping-in-linux-mint-19-taskbar/</guid>
      <description>Simple fluff here. Took me a while to hunt down this feature. I switched to the latest Mint, and the applications all group by type like this -
If you have an Incognito tab or multiple folders, its a bit annoying for me to hover and flip through and I like to click rather than Alt+Tab or some other window switching method.
To change it:
 Right click empty space on the taskbar, click + Add Applets to Panel  Select Grouped Window List from the next menu and click the gear icon next to it In the next window untoggle the Group windows by application option   And thats it, now all your applications will be spread out even with multiples of the same app open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker Rank Special Multiple</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/07/hacker-rank-special-multiple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/07/hacker-rank-special-multiple/</guid>
      <description>Not a hard one: You are given an integer N. Can you find the least positive integer X made up of only 9&#39;s and 0&#39;s, such that, X is a multiple of N?
Any number consisting of just 9s and 0s is divisible by 9. I see a few ways to use that, also 9s and 0s are two unique characters, so another way would be to process numbers are strings matching those characters rather than evaluating every multiple of N until you hit one thats divisible by 9, as something can be divisible by 9 but not be only 9s and 0s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Geese - Nature&#39;s Satanic Cult</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/06/canadian-geese-natures-satanic-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/06/canadian-geese-natures-satanic-cult/</guid>
      <description>Geese are a scourge Since my wife and I are getting old, we&amp;rsquo;ve taken up gardening and with age comes us getting better at it. So of course this year I wanted to try the Three Sisters method of planting. I would plant corn, beans and squash together to maximize the output for a given area, and it would take a bit less work.
In the spirit of overdoing it, our neighbor was kind enough to use his big Kobota tractor with a tiller attachment to grind up a big area in our backyard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 3 - The End</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/04/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-3-the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/04/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-3-the-end/</guid>
      <description>Out the door Leading up to the first weekend away, we called and sent an email to the case worker. We wanted confirmation the children would be able to go to their Aunt&amp;rsquo;s for the weekend. Instead of confirmation (which we had gotten verbally), my wife got a bit of a dressing down over the phone (or at one of their schedule visits, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember which). Paraphrasing - the worker more or less said no one involved had the right to make those decisions except her/Cuyahoga county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-2/</guid>
      <description>On the way Despite the stress for everyone involved, we were aware our placements would be leaving us by summer, at least as of January. In February, we were summoned for what was called a staffing meeting. This is where various parties related to the case gather together and discuss things that could be in an email.
The meeting did not really concern us, though my wife and I were both present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Foster Placement Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/03/our-first-foster-placement-pt.-1/</guid>
      <description>Foster care sure was something On October 26th, we got a call about our first foster placement. In the month prior, we had taken a few weekend cases for respite care. Respite care is babysitting for other foster parents. Then they can take a break or take care of a few things. Leading into the proper placement, respite care went ok. It was a bit hard since the kids were so young and couldn&amp;rsquo;t bond with us over a weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Sucks</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2019/02/twitter-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2019/02/twitter-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Likely all social media sucks, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure my opinion here is not new. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a year on a Twitter account following a couple rules:
  Avoid reading popular accounts/threads. If there are thousands of people involved, its pointless noise.
  Stay local. Only follow local/state level people in Ohio. That narrows the focus.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few good threads on Twitter. Otherwise, its nothing but a hot take echo chamber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random thoughts</title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/2018/12/random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/2018/12/random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This timeline is weird If you&amp;rsquo;d told me 15 years ago, I would have two kids and be fostering two more, I&amp;rsquo;d have called you nuts. I&amp;rsquo;ve turned into everyone&amp;rsquo;s dad. The stampede of footsteps every morning is my alarm clock. And my day is a constant stream of the question &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo;.
Expectation never meets reality, and I&amp;rsquo;m not unhappy at all. People think you can make precarious plans and follow them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://martysohio.com/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martysohio.com/1/01/</guid>
      <description>title: &amp;ldquo;Stop worrying so much about Bernie Sanders&amp;rdquo; thumbnailImagePosition: left thumbnailImage: /img/thumb_guy.png metaAlignment: center coverMeta: out date: 2020-02-22 categories:
 Democratic Primary tags: random politics BERN   With the Democratic Presidential primary underway, there have been endless attacks on every candidate. But with Sander&amp;rsquo;s currently winning, there has been constant scare mongering about his policies and potential divisiveness. However, I believe the hype is overblown by our media. By and large, polling for the cornerstones of Sander&amp;rsquo;s platform (and to a lesser extent Warren&amp;rsquo;s) show a majority of Americans favor not only socialist policies, but also upsetting the current power structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>